[{"id":5,"question":"Who is the father of modern physics?","option1":"Isaac Newton","option2":"Galileo galilei","option3":"Albert Einstein","option4":"Copernicus","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Albert Einstein","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":6,"question":"The Newton’s third law is applicable when:","option1":"bodies are at rest","option2":"bodies are in motion","option3":"bodies are in the air","option4":"bodies are at rest or in motion","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"bodies are at rest or in motion","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":7,"question":"Which of the following is an example of application of force?","option1":"when a body at rest starts moving","option2":"when a moving body stops","option3":"when moving body changes its direction","option4":"All of the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"All of the above","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":8,"question":"\nThe working principle of a washing machine is","option1":"reverse osmosis ","option2":" diffusion","option3":"centrifugation","option4":"dialysis ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"centrifugation","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":9,"question":"The speed of light will be minimum while passing through","option1":"water ","option2":"vaccum","option3":" air ","option4":" glass ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" glass ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":10,"question":"It is more difficult to walk on ice than on a concrete road because ","option1":" there is very little friction between the ice and feet pressing it ","option2":"ice is soft when compared to concrete ","option3":"there is more friction between the ice and feer ","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" there is very little friction between the ice and feet pressing it ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":11,"question":"Rain drops acquire spherical shape due to ","option1":"viscosity ","option2":"surface tension ","option3":"friction ","option4":"elasticity ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"surface tension ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":12,"question":"What is the SI unit of pressure","option1":"Pascal ","option2":" Dyne","option3":"Newton ","option4":"Jule ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Pascal ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":13,"question":"Catalytic converters are generally made from","option1":"Carbon","option2":"Alkaline metals","option3":"Transition metals","option4":"Hydrogen","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Transition metals","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":14,"question":"Mercury and sodium street lamps light up because of","option1":"Atomic absorption","option2":"Atomic emission","option3":"Electron absorption","option4":"Electron emission","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Atomic emission","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":15,"question":" \n\nOptical fiber works on the principle of","option1":"Scattering ","option2":"interference ","option3":"total internal reflection ","option4":"refraction ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"total internal reflection ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":16,"question":"Most commonly used bleaching agent is","option1":"Alcohol","option2":"Chlorine","option3":"Sodium chloride","option4":"Carbon dioxide","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Chlorine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":17,"question":"One astronomical unit is the average distance between","option1":"Earth and the Sun ","option2":"Earth and the Moon ","option3":"Jupiter and the Sun ","option4":" Pluto and the Sun ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Earth and the Sun ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":18,"question":"When a helium atom loses an electron it becomes","option1":"An alpha particle","option2":"A proton","option3":"A positive helium ion","option4":"A negative helium ion","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"A positive helium ion","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":19,"question":"Ball bearings are used in cycles, scooters etc to","option1":" Increase the friction between the wheel and the axle ","option2":" Reduce the friction between the wheel and the axle ","option3":"Reduce the friction between ground and the wheel","option4":"None of the above ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Reduce the friction between the wheel and the axle ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":20,"question":"Purest form of iron is","option1":"Cast iron","option2":"Steel","option3":"Pig iron","option4":"Wrought iron","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Wrought iron","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":21,"question":"Pick out the only scalar quantity","option1":"power ","option2":"Electric field ","option3":"magnetic momentum ","option4":"average velocity ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"power ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":22,"question":"Which of the following is used in pencils","option1":"Graphite","option2":"Sulphur","option3":"Phosphorus","option4":"Charcol","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Graphite","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":23,"question":"Which of the following is not a noble gas","option1":"Hydrogen","option2":"Helium","option3":"Neon","option4":"Argon","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Hydrogen","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":24,"question":"Ink is prepared from","option1":"Dye","option2":"Tannin","option3":"Starch","option4":"Latex","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Tannin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":25,"question":"Formic acid is produced by","option1":"White ants","option2":"Cockroaches","option3":"Red ants","option4":"Mosquitoes","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Red ants","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":26,"question":"Joule is Equal to","option1":"10^3 ergs","option2":"10^6 ergs ","option3":" 10^7 ergs ","option4":" 10^5 ergs ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" 10^7 ergs ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":27,"question":"Cement is formed by strongly heating a mixture of","option1":"Limestone and graphite","option2":"Limestone and clay","option3":"Chalk and graphite","option4":"Clay and graphite","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Limestone and clay","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":28,"question":"When body is accelerated","option1":" its velocity never changes","option2":"its speed always changes ","option3":"its direction always changes","option4":"its speed may or maynot change ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"its speed may or maynot change ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":29,"question":"\nWhich Color has the Longest Wavelength?","option1":" Violet ","option2":"Yellow ","option3":"Red ","option4":" White ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Red ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":30,"question":"Who is credited with the invention of the modern periodic table","option1":"Nobel","option2":"Lavoisier","option3":"Mendel","option4":"Mendeleev","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Mendeleev","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":31,"question":"Decibel is the unit of","option1":"speed of light ","option2":" intensity of sound ","option3":"intensity of heat ","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" intensity of sound ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":32,"question":"Which of these elements is a nonmetal","option1":"Sulfur","option2":"Manganese","option3":"Aluminium","option4":"Beryllium","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Sulfur","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":33,"question":"The symbol Ag stands for which element","option1":"Gallium","option2":"Magnesium","option3":"Gold","option4":"Silver","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Silver","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":34,"question":"Which of the following is a vector quantity","option1":"momentum ","option2":"pressure ","option3":"Energy ","option4":"work ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"momentum ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":35,"question":"\nAll of the following are amino acids except","option1":"Tryptophan","option2":"Leucine","option3":"Tyrosine","option4":"Adenine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Adenine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":36,"question":"Which of the following is a scalar quantity","option1":"electric current ","option2":"electric field ","option3":"Acceleration ","option4":"linear momentum","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"electric current ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":37,"question":"Which liquid is the most viscous?","option1":"Water ","option2":"Diesel ","option3":"Milk ","option4":" Oil ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Oil ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":38,"question":"The ratio of pure gold in 18 carat gold is","option1":"60 percentage","option2":"75 percentage","option3":"80 percentage","option4":"90 percentage","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"75 percentage","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":39,"question":"\nAn object that has kinetic energy must be","option1":"At an elevated position ","option2":"Falling ","option3":"At rest ","option4":"Moving ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Moving ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":40,"question":"Gobar gas contains mainly","option1":"Methane","option2":"Ethylene","option3":"Propylene","option4":"Acetylene","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Methane","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":41,"question":"Which of the following elements is non-radioactive","option1":"Uranium","option2":"Thorium","option3":"Plutonium","option4":"Zirconium","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Zirconium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":42,"question":"Which one of the following organic compounds has fruity smrll","option1":"Alcohol","option2":"Aldehyde","option3":"Ester","option4":"Ether","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Ester","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":43,"question":"Which of the following has the highest frequency?","option1":"Cosmic rays ","option2":"X-rays ","option3":"Radio waves ","option4":"Microwaves ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Cosmic rays ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":44,"question":"Quartz is made up of","option1":"Calcium sulphate","option2":"Calcium silicate","option3":"Sodium sulphate","option4":"Sodium silicate","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Sodium silicate","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":45,"question":"Water has maximum density at............","option1":" 0 C ","option2":"-15 C ","option3":"4C","option4":"15C","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"4C","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":46,"question":"Saccharine is Made up of ","option1":"Toluene","option2":"Phenol","option3":"Propane","option4":"Butane","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Toluene","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":47,"question":"What is the colour of emarald","option1":"Violet","option2":"Yellow","option3":"Deep green","option4":"Prussian blue","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Deep green","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":48,"question":"Light year is a unit of","option1":"time","option2":"speed of light","option3":"distance","option4":"mass","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"distance","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":49,"question":"PVC is obtained by the polymerisation of","option1":"Propane","option2":"Styrene","option3":"Vinyl chloride","option4":"Acetylene","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Vinyl chloride","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":50,"question":"An atom bomb based upon the principal of ________","option1":"Nuclear fission ","option2":"Nuclear fussion","option3":"Controlled chain reaction ","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Nuclear fission ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":51,"question":"Which variety of glass is heat resistant","option1":"Hard glass","option2":"Flint glass","option3":"Pyrex glass","option4":"Bottle glass","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Pyrex glass","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":52,"question":"What is the element required for solar energy conversion","option1":"Beryllium","option2":"Tantalum","option3":"Silicon","option4":"Ultra pure carbon","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Silicon","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":53,"question":"Which law is also called law of inertia ?","option1":"Newton first law ","option2":"Newton second law ","option3":"Newton third law ","option4":"All of above ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Newton first law ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":54,"question":"Which of the following imparts deep blue colour to glass","option1":"Cobalt oxide","option2":"Cupric oxide","option3":"Ferrous oxide","option4":"Nickel oxide","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Cupric oxide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":55,"question":"Sound waves cannot travel in","option1":" Vacuum ","option2":"water","option3":"Glass","option4":"hydrogen gas","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Vacuum ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":56,"question":"Which element is obtained from the sea algae","option1":"Argon","option2":"Sulphur","option3":"Vanadium","option4":"Lodine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Lodine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":57,"question":"Which of the following is not a component of chlorophyll","option1":"Hydrogen","option2":"Magnesium","option3":"Carbon","option4":"Calcium","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Calcium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":58,"question":"The fourth state of matter is known as","option1":"Gas","option2":"Vapour","option3":"Plasma","option4":"Electrons","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Plasma","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":59,"question":"Which of the following is the petroleum wax","option1":"Bees wax","option2":"Carnauba wax","option3":"Paraffin wax","option4":"Jojoba wax","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Paraffin wax","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":60,"question":"Max well is the unit of","option1":"intensity of magnetization ","option2":" permeability ","option3":"magnetic flux ","option4":"magnetic susceptibility ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"magnetic flux ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":61,"question":"By-product obtained by soap-industry is","option1":"Caustic soda","option2":"Glycerol","option3":"Naphthalene","option4":"Caustic potash","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Glycerol","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":62,"question":"Which silver salt is used for making film for photography","option1":"Silver bromide","option2":"Silver chloride","option3":"Silver sulphate","option4":"Silver nitrate","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Silver bromide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":63,"question":"For determination of the age of which among the following is carbon dating method used","option1":"Fossils","option2":"Rocks","option3":"Trees","option4":"1 and  2 above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"1 and  2 above","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":64,"question":"\nElectron was discovered by","option1":"Ernest Rutherford","option2":"Max Planck","option3":"Joseph Thomson","option4":"Albert Einstein","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Joseph Thomson","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":65,"question":"Which acid is manufactured using sawdust","option1":"Oxalic acid","option2":"Citric acid","option3":"Acetic acid","option4":"Butyric acid","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Oxalic acid","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":66,"question":"The polymer used in making plastic crockery is","option1":"Decron","option2":"Nylon","option3":"Bakelite","option4":"Melamine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Melamine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":67,"question":"Vulcanisation of rubber is carried out by adding","option1":"Sulphur","option2":"Phosphorus","option3":"Carbon","option4":"Ozone","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Sulphur","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":68,"question":"Diamond and graphite ls are","option1":"Allotropes","option2":"Isomorphous","option3":"Isomers","option4":"Isobars","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Allotropes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":69,"question":"The most electronegative element among the following is","option1":"Sodium","option2":"Bromine","option3":"Fluorine","option4":"Oxygen","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Fluorine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":70,"question":"Which one is a naturally occurring noble gas","option1":"Sodium","option2":"Potassium","option3":"Argon","option4":"Boron","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Argon","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":71,"question":"Who is the father of modern chemistry","option1":"John Dalton","option2":"Robert Boyle","option3":"Antoine Lavoisier","option4":"Democritus","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Antoine Lavoisier","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":72,"question":"Which one element from below list is liquid at room temperature","option1":"Zinc","option2":"Argon","option3":"Lead","option4":"Bromine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Bromine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":73,"question":"Liquid Nitrogen boils at","option1":"77 Kelvin","option2":"82 Kelvin","option3":"54 Kelvin","option4":"97 Kelvin","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"77 Kelvin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":74,"question":"Total number of elements in a periodic table","option1":"112","option2":"115","option3":"118","option4":"127","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"118","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":75,"question":"How many neutrons does iron have","option1":"8","option2":"13","option3":"26","option4":"30","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"30","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":76,"question":"Which one is the simplest form of alkane","option1":"Propane","option2":"Butane","option3":"Methane","option4":"Decane","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Methane","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":77,"question":"Why does the sea appear blue in colour?","option1":"Reflection of the sun light from water surface ","option2":"Interference of the sun light from water surface","option3":" Scattering of the sunlight by water molecules ","option4":"refraction of the sun light ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Scattering of the sunlight by water molecules ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":78,"question":"Which of the following is the most active chemically","option1":"Chlorine","option2":"Flourine","option3":"Lithium","option4":"Iodine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Flourine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":79,"question":"Which of the following is an alkaline earth metal","option1":"Potassium","option2":"Lead","option3":"Copper","option4":"Calcium","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Calcium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":80,"question":"Which of the following is also known as wood alcohol","option1":"Methanol","option2":"Ethanol","option3":"Propanal","option4":"Butanol","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Methanol","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":81,"question":"What is the common name of analgesic and antipyretic drug acetylsalicylic acid","option1":"Paracetamol","option2":"Aspirin","option3":"Wintergreen","option4":"Trazodone","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Aspirin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":82,"question":"The substrate of photo-respiration is","option1":"Pyueilvic acid","option2":"Glucose ","option3":"Fructose ","option4":"Glycolate","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Pyueilvic acid","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":83,"question":"Which one of these animals is jawless","option1":"Shark ","option2":"Myxine","option3":"Trygon","option4":"Sphyrna","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Myxine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":84,"question":"Afla-toxins are produced by","option1":"Bacteria ","option2":"Fungi ","option3":"Viruses ","option4":"Algae ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Fungi ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":85,"question":"The maximum fixation of solar energy is done by","option1":"Greenplants","option2":"Fungi ","option3":"Bacteria ","option4":"Protozoa","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Greenplants","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":86,"question":"Allantois of embryo helps in ","option1":"Excretion ","option2":"Digestion ","option3":"Respiration ","option4":"Protection ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Excretion ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":87,"question":"Which of the animals belongs to mollusca","option1":"Hare ","option2":"Haleotis","option3":"Hydra ","option4":"Hyla","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Haleotis","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":88,"question":"Photoperiodism affects ","option1":"Vegetative growth ","option2":"Fruiting ","option3":"Flowering ","option4":"All of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"All of these ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":89,"question":"Haemolymph is observed in ","option1":"Arthropods ","option2":"Echinoderms","option3":"Ascaris","option4":"Analids","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Arthropods ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":90,"question":"The virus without capsid but only with nucleic acid is called ","option1":"Capsomeri","option2":"Nucleoid","option3":"Prion","option4":"Virion","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Nucleoid","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":91,"question":"The sleeping sickness is caused by ","option1":"Escherichia","option2":"Neisseria","option3":"Entamoeba","option4":"Trypanasoma","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Trypanasoma","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":92,"question":"Name the tissues that transports food to various parts of a plant ","option1":"Parenchyma","option2":"Xylem","option3":"Phloem","option4":"Sclerenchyma","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Phloem","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":93,"question":"Chlorophyll in photosynthetic prokaryotic bacteria is associated with ","option1":"Plastids","option2":"Membraneous vesicles","option3":"Nucleoids","option4":"Chromosomes ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Membraneous vesicles","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":94,"question":"Which cell organelles is known as \"suicide bags\" of a cell","option1":"Lysosomes","option2":"Plastids","option3":"Endoplasmic reticulum","option4":"Mitochondria","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Lysosomes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":95,"question":"How many laws of physics are there?","option1":"5","option2":"4","option3":"3","option4":"2","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"3","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":96,"question":"What is unit of Astronomical distance ?","option1":" light year ","option2":"angstrom ","option3":"weber ","option4":"lux","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" light year ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":97,"question":"SI unit of Luminious intensity is","option1":"Lumen ","option2":"Lux ","option3":" Candela ","option4":"Watt","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Candela ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":98,"question":"Radian is used to measure","option1":"Temperature ","option2":" Intensity of Flame ","option3":"Angle ","option4":"Solid Angle ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Angle ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":99,"question":"Which results in an increase in power?","option1":" doing more work in less time. ","option2":"doing less work in more time. ","option3":"doing less work in less time. ","option4":" doing more work in more time. ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" doing more work in less time. ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":100,"question":"Scalar Quantities are","option1":"physical quantities which have magnitude only and no direction ","option2":" physical quantities which have no magnitude only and only direction ","option3":" physical quantities which have magnitude only and direction","option4":" physical quantities which have no magnitude and no direction ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"physical quantities which have magnitude only and no direction ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":101,"question":"What color does blue and yellow make?","option1":"Green ","option2":"Black ","option3":"Red","option4":"White","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Green ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":102,"question":"Frictional force acts in ","option1":" the same direction as the motion ","option2":" the opposite direction of the motion ","option3":" all the directions ","option4":" upward direction","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" the opposite direction of the motion ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":103,"question":"Compressions and Rarefactions are characteristic of","option1":"Longitudinal waves","option2":"Transverse waves","option3":"Both A and B","option4":"Neither of A and B","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Longitudinal waves","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":104,"question":"Which planet has the lowest density?","option1":"Earth ","option2":"Jupiter ","option3":"Saturn ","option4":"Neptune","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Saturn ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":105,"question":"When a bullet is fired from a gun ","option1":"the gun moves forward ","option2":"the gun jumps up ","option3":" the gun does not move ","option4":"the gun recoils with the same momentum as the bullet","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"the gun recoils with the same momentum as the bullet","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":106,"question":"Which of the following is not a transverse wave?","option1":" Light waves","option2":" Radio waves","option3":" Sound waves","option4":"All the above ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Sound waves","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":107,"question":"During thunderstorm you are travelling in a car. To protect yourself from the lightning you will have to ","option1":" remain in the car ","option2":"get out of the car and lie flat in the ground ","option3":"abandon the car and take shelter under a nearby tree ","option4":" touch the nearest electric pole ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" remain in the car ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":108,"question":"In which year where the first laws of cricket believed to have been written","option1":"1806","option2":"1774","option3":"1709","option4":"1900","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"1774","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":109,"question":"Which of the following is a Heterogeneous Mixture?","option1":" Air ","option2":" Table salt","option3":"Soda ","option4":"Brass ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Soda ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":110,"question":"Which is a common first indicator of an approaching thunderstorm?","option1":"too hot ","option2":" heavy wind","option3":"a buildup of dark clouds ","option4":" lightning ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"a buildup of dark clouds ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":111,"question":"Who is the leading wicket taker in one day internationals","option1":"L Malinga","option2":"Wasim Akram","option3":"M Muralitharan ","option4":"G McGrath ","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"M Muralitharan ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":112,"question":"What is unit of Viscosity ?","option1":" coulomb ","option2":"newton second per square meter ","option3":" watt per meter per degree celcius ","option4":" joule per kilogram per Kelvin ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"newton second per square meter ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":113,"question":"If a barometric reading is falling, this usually indicates what","option1":" Increasing pressure","option2":" Decreasing pressure ","option3":" No pressure","option4":"None ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Decreasing pressure ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":114,"question":"The force that keeps a body in a circular motion called ","option1":" the centripetal force ","option2":"the centrifugual force ","option3":"the frictional force ","option4":" all the above ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" the centripetal force ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":115,"question":"Lightning is produced when ","option1":"Similar charges of electricity rush towards each other and then get repelled ","option2":"clouds strike against impurities in air and the friction burns up these impurities ","option3":"strong opposite charges in different clouds break down the resistance offered by the intervening air","option4":"water vapour produces electricity in the clouds ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"strong opposite charges in different clouds break down the resistance offered by the intervening air","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":116,"question":"Heat is associated with","option1":" K.E of random motion of molecules ","option2":"K.E of orderly motion of molecules ","option3":"Total K.E of random and orderly motion of molecules","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" K.E of random motion of molecules ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":117,"question":"Lens is made up of which glass","option1":"Ordinary glass","option2":" Pyrex glass ","option3":" Flint glass ","option4":"Cobalt glass ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Flint glass ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":118,"question":"Sound travels fastest in","option1":"Vacuum ","option2":"Air","option3":"Glass","option4":"Wate","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Glass","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":119,"question":"Which resource is both renewable and inexpensive?","option1":"Sunlight ","option2":"Coal ","option3":"Gold ","option4":"Minerals ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Sunlight ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":120,"question":"Electrical Pressure is also called","option1":" Current ","option2":"Voltage","option3":"Resistance ","option4":" Power ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Voltage","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":121,"question":"Which pair holds the record for the highest partnership in the history of test cricket","option1":"CC Hunte-GS Sobers","option2":"Mudassar Nazar-Javed Miandad","option3":"K Sangakkara-M Jayawardene","option4":"B Stokes-J Bairstow","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"K Sangakkara-M Jayawardene","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":122,"question":"Which of the following is not an aerosol?","option1":" mud ","option2":"dust ","option3":"smoke","option4":" fog ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" mud ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":123,"question":"Lux is the SI unit of","option1":"luminous flux ","option2":"luminous efficiency ","option3":" decreases slightly ","option4":" decreases rapidly","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" decreases slightly ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":124,"question":"Speed of sound is maximum in which among the following?","option1":" Gases","option2":"Vaccum ","option3":"Liquids","option4":" Solids ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Solids ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":125,"question":"Which color has the highest frequency?","option1":"Violet ","option2":" Red","option3":" Indigo ","option4":" Green ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Violet ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":126,"question":" Who took most catches in an ODI as a substitute?","option1":"R Murray","option2":"JG Bracewell","option3":"R Dravid","option4":"J Rhodes","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"JG Bracewell","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":127,"question":"In which layer is the pressure the highest?","option1":" Ionosphere ","option2":"Stratosphere ","option3":"Troposphere ","option4":" Inner core ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":" Inner core ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":128,"question":"RADAR is used for","option1":"detecting and locating the position of objects such as Aeroplanes ","option2":"locating submerged submarines","option3":"locating geostationary satellites ","option4":"receiving a signals in a radio receiver ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"detecting and locating the position of objects such as Aeroplanes ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":129,"question":"Nuclear Fission is caused by the impact of ","option1":" Electron ","option2":"Neutron ","option3":" Proton ","option4":"Deutron ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Neutron ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":130,"question":"Which of the following is not present in animal crlls","option1":"Cell walls","option2":"Mitochondria","option3":"Ribosomes","option4":"Cytoplasm","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Cell walls","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":131,"question":"Which is not a part of the digestive system","option1":"Small intestine","option2":"Rectum","option3":"Pharynx","option4":"Spleen","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Spleen","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":132,"question":"Which is the largest cricket stadium in the world","option1":"Melbourne cricket ground","option2":"Sardar Patel cricket stadium","option3":"Eden park","option4":"The gabba","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Sardar Patel cricket stadium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":133,"question":"Presence of which among the following salts in water causes\"Blue Baby Syndrome\"","option1":"Sulphates","option2":"Chlorides","option3":"Carbonates","option4":"Nitrates","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Nitrates","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":134,"question":"In which of the following plants,you can find Leghemoglobin","option1":"Wheat","option2":"Soyabean","option3":"Potato","option4":"Brinjal","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Soyabean","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":135,"question":"What is the Ph value of human blood?","option1":"7.40","option2":"7","option3":"0","option4":"8","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"7.40","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":136,"question":"Which team holds the record for highest innings total in ODI","option1":"England","option2":"South Africa","option3":"Australia","option4":"West Indies","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"England","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":137,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most centuries in first-class cricket?","option1":"Sachin Tendulkar","option2":"B Lara","option3":"Don Bradman","option4":"Jack Hobbs","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Jack Hobbs","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":138,"question":"What is the longest movie ever made?","option1":"Modern Times Forever","option2":"Logistics","option3":"Beijing 2003","option4":"Cinematon","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Logistics","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":139,"question":"The rarest blood group is","option1":"O negative","option2":"B negative","option3":"AB positive","option4":"AB negative","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"AB negative","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":140,"question":"Who is the youngest best actor Oscar winner?","option1":"Jackie Cooper","option2":"Quvenzhané Wallis","option3":"Timothy Hutton","option4":"Adrien Brody","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Adrien Brody","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":141,"question":"The metal present in chlorophyll is","option1":"Calcium","option2":"Aluminium","option3":"Magnesium","option4":"Zinc","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Magnesium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":142,"question":"Which player had taken first hat-trick in the history of Test cricket?","option1":"George Lehmann","option2":"Fred Spofforth","option3":"Jack Hearne","option4":"Johnny Briggs","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Fred Spofforth","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":143,"question":"The number of chromosomes in the human gene is","option1":"23","option2":"48","option3":"46","option4":"24","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"46","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":144,"question":"Viticulture is related with","option1":"Grapes","option2":"Pine Apple","option3":"Orange","option4":"Strawberry","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Grapes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":145,"question":"The longest and largest bone in the human body is","option1":"Spinal cord","option2":"Humerus","option3":"Fibula","option4":"Femur","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Femur","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":146,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most test runs in a calendar year?","option1":"V. V. S. Laxman","option2":"Sachin Tendulkar","option3":"Mohamed Yusuf","option4":"S Smith","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Mohamed Yusuf","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":147,"question":"What woman has won the most Oscars?","option1":"Edith Head ","option2":"Cate Blanchett","option3":"Ingrid Bergman","option4":"Lauren Bacall","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Edith Head ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":148,"question":"Plants receive their nutrients mainly from","option1":"Chlorophyll","option2":"Atmosphere","option3":"Light","option4":"Soil","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Soil","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":149,"question":"Movement of cell against concentration gradient is called","option1":"Osmosis","option2":"Active transport","option3":"Diffusion","option4":"Passive transport","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Active transport","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":150,"question":"What was Disney’s first film to win an Academy Award?","option1":"America the beautiful","option2":"Flowers and Trees","option3":"Magic Journeys","option4":"The Making of Me","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Flowers and Trees","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":151,"question":"Which of these is not a dehiscent plant","option1":"Pea","option2":"Bean","option3":"Magnolia","option4":"Banana","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Banana","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":152,"question":"How much blood is in the human body","option1":"2.2 litres","option2":"5.7 litres","option3":"8.1 litres","option4":"9.3 litres","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"5.7 litres","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":153,"question":"First programme telecast on Doordarshan is","option1":"Krishi Darshan","option2":"Asian Games","option3":"The peacock call","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Krishi Darshan","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":154,"question":"How many taste buds do young people have","option1":"1000","option2":"10000","option3":"100000","option4":"1000000","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"100000","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":155,"question":"How many basic tastes can humans sense","option1":"1","option2":"4","option3":"5","option4":"6","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"5","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":156,"question":"What sensory function do the ears provide other than hearing","option1":"Smell","option2":"Balance","option3":"Temperature","option4":"Radiation","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Balance","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"Keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":157,"question":"Who played the leading role in the film Raja Harishchandra","option1":"Vithal","option2":"Prithviraj Kapoor","option3":"DD Dabke","option4":"None of the these","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"DD Dabke","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":158,"question":"Who was the first Indian actress won best actress award in an International film festival","option1":"Suchithra Sen","option2":"Waheeda Rahman","option3":"Nutan","option4":"Nargis Dutt","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Suchithra Sen","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":159,"question":"Which Bollywood films with highest number of songs","option1":"Neel Kamal","option2":"Indra Sabha","option3":"Alam Ara","option4":"Kishan Kanaya","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Indra Sabha","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":160,"question":"Who is the first Indian movie star to be featured on the cover of time magazine","option1":"Zeenat Aman","option2":"Parveen Babi","option3":"Ashwariya Rai","option4":"Amir khan","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Parveen Babi","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":161,"question":"Which one is the longest film in india by running time","option1":"Thavamai Thavamirundhu","option2":"Mera Naam Joker","option3":"LOC Kargil","option4":"Parthiban kanavu","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Thavamai Thavamirundhu","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":162,"question":"First Indian movie that premeired at USA","option1":"Mother India","option2":"Amar Jyothi","option3":"Ram Rajya","option4":"Awaara","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Ram Rajya","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":163,"question":"First Indian movie submitted for Oscar","option1":"Mother India","option2":"The guide","option3":"Madhumathi","option4":"guru","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Mother India","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":164,"question":" Which cricketer had scored fastest century in ODI cricket?","option1":"Vivian Richards","option2":"Corey Anderson","option3":"AB de Villiers","option4":"Shahid Afridi","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"AB de Villiers","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"govind@quizapp.com"},{"id":165,"question":"First Indian sound film","option1":"Alam Ara","option2":"Raja Harishchandra","option3":"Kishan Kanya","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Alam Ara","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":166,"question":"From which year Indian Government sponsored National Film Award","option1":"1972","option2":"1973","option3":"1984","option4":"1980","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"1973","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":167,"question":"First Indian to win an Oscar award","option1":"Bhanu Athaiya","option2":"AR Rahman","option3":"Rasul Pookuty","option4":"Nargis datt","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Bhanu Athaiya","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":168,"question":"Lumiere brothers, the pioneer of motion pictures are from","option1":"French","option2":"USA","option3":"England","option4":"Germany","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"French","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":169,"question":"From which year Oscar award was first awarded","option1":"1921","option2":"1935","option3":"1922","option4":"1929","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"1929","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":170,"question":"Which of the following is a large blood vessel that carries blood away from the heart? ","option1":"Thiamine","option2":"Riboflavin","option3":"Folic acid","option4":" Ascorbic acid","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Ascorbic acid","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":171,"question":"Fungi are plants that lack:","option1":"Oxygen","option2":" Carbon dioxide","option3":" Chlorophyll","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Chlorophyll","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":172,"question":"What makes a reptile a reptile?","option1":"Cold blooded","option2":"Warm Blooded","option3":"Non-Hearing","option4":"Egg-laying","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Egg-laying","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":173,"question":"Which blood vessels have the smallest diameter?","option1":"Capillaries","option2":"Arterioles","option3":" Venules","option4":"Lymphatic","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Capillaries","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":174,"question":"Which of the following is an air-borne disease? ","option1":"Measles","option2":"Typhoid","option3":"Pink eye","option4":" None of the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Measles","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":175,"question":"Which of the following hormones is a steroid?","option1":"Estrogen","option2":"Glucagon","option3":" Insulin","option4":"Oxytocin","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Estrogen","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":176,"question":" Which one of the following is not a function of the liver?","option1":" Regulation of blood suga","option2":"Enzyme activation","option3":"Detoxification","option4":"Reproduction","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Reproduction","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":177,"question":"The human appendix is attached with …","option1":"The large intestine","option2":"The small intestine","option3":"The gall bladder","option4":"The stomach","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"The large intestine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":178,"question":" From the evolutionary point of view, which among the following is much closer to the man?","option1":"Dolphin","option2":"Frog","option3":"Shark","option4":"Tortoise","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Dolphin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":179,"question":"The deficiency of …………… causes Ariboflavinosis.","option1":"Vitamin A","option2":"Vitamin B1","option3":"Vitamin B2","option4":" Vitamin B3","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Vitamin B2","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":180,"question":"The deficiency of …………… causes sterility (in men).","option1":"Vitamin C","option2":" Vitamin D","option3":" Vitamin E","option4":"Vitamin K","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Vitamin E","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":181,"question":"………. Has the respiratory skin.","option1":"Fish","option2":" Frog","option3":"Shark","option4":" Whale","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Frog","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":182,"question":"Which among the following refers by the phonoreceptor?","option1":"Feel","option2":"Touch","option3":"Sound","option4":"Smell","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Sound","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":183,"question":"Which among the following is the correct measurement of normal systolic blood pressure?","option1":" 60","option2":"80","option3":"120","option4":" 180","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"120","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":184,"question":"Deficiency of ………………… causes the Goiter (enlarged thyroid gland).","option1":" Magnesium","option2":" Iodine","option3":" Calcium","option4":" Iron","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Iodine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":185,"question":"The function of Biceps is to ……","option1":"Raise and rotates the arm","option2":" Draw the shoulder forward and rotate the arm inward","option3":" Bend the arm at the elbow","option4":" Straighten the elbow","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Bend the arm at the elbow","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":186,"question":"Animal without red blood cells","option1":"Frog","option2":"Earthworm","option3":"Snake","option4":"Peacock","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Earthworm","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":187,"question":"Chambered heart is occurs in","option1":"Leech","option2":"Earthworm","option3":"Snail","option4":"Cockroach","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Cockroach","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":188,"question":" Deficiency of ………………… causes the Goiter (enlarged thyroid gland).","option1":" Magnesium","option2":"Iodine","option3":" Calcium","option4":" Iron","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Iodine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":189,"question":"The phenomenon of summer sleep by animals is called","option1":"Hibernation","option2":"Aestivation","option3":"Laziness","option4":"Lethargy","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Aestivation","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":190,"question":"Bone deformities occur due to the excess intake of","option1":"Phosphorous","option2":"Potassium","option3":"Fatty acid","option4":"Fluorine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Fluorine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":191,"question":"Number of eyes found in Earthworm","option1":"One","option2":"Many","option3":"No eye","option4":"Two","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"No eye","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":192,"question":"The outer membrane that covers the brain is","option1":"Myelin Sheath","option2":"Dura mater","option3":"Arachnoid membrane","option4":"Pia mater","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Dura mater","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":193,"question":"The hormone that helps in parthenocarpy","option1":"Abscisic acid","option2":"Gibberellin","option3":"Ethylene","option4":"Cytokinin","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Gibberellin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":194,"question":"Food chain is - ","option1":"relationship between auto-tropic ","option2":"exchange of genetic material between two organisms ","option3":"passage of food (and thus energy) from one organism to another ","option4":"modern entrepreneur establishment providing food outlets ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"passage of food (and thus energy) from one organism to another ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":195,"question":"Vivipary is defined as germination","option1":"During storage","option2":"Within the fruit","option3":"With cotyledons coming out of the soil","option4":"With cotyledons remaining inside the soil","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Within the fruit","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":196,"question":"Tikka disease is related with the crop","option1":"Mustard","option2":"Paddy","option3":"Ground nut","option4":"All of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Ground nut","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":197,"question":"Botany is also known as ","option1":"Phytology","option2":"phycology","option3":"Pedology","option4":"Plantophyta","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Phytology","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":198,"question":"A very high frequency wave originating in the nucleus of atom and travelling with the speed of light is the","option1":"alpha rays","option2":"X-rays","option3":"beta rays","option4":"gamma rays","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"gamma rays","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":199,"question":"Chemically dry ice is","option1":"solid sulphur dioxide","option2":"solid carbon dioxide","option3":"a mixture of ice and common salt","option4":"ice formed from pure distilled water","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"solid carbon dioxide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":200,"question":"The gland that is close to Trachea","option1":"Pancreas","option2":"Liver","option3":"Adrrenal","option4":"Thyroid","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Thyroid","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":201,"question":"Which substance is produced by Fermentation?","option1":"Chlorine","option2":"Sulphur dioxide","option3":"Carbon dioxide","option4":"Nitrogen dioxide","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Carbon dioxide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":202,"question":"Hardest part of the human body","option1":"Tooth Enamel","option2":"Femur","option3":"Temporal bone of skull","option4":"Knee bone","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Tooth Enamel","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":203,"question":"Rusting of iron is an example of\n","option1":"rapid oxidation","option2":"spontaneous combustion","option3":"reduction","option4":"slow oxidation","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"slow oxidation","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":204,"question":"Which of the following is an Autotroph ","option1":"Fish","option2":"Algae","option3":"Butterfly","option4":"Mushroom","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Algae","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":205,"question":"Nuclear membrane is absent in","option1":"Volvox","option2":"Penicillium","option3":"Agaricus","option4":"Nostoc","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Nostoc","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":207,"question":"Hindustani classical music is broken into groups of notes.What would one of these groups of notes be called","option1":"Taalam","option2":"Taal","option3":"Note Group","option4":"Raaga","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Raaga","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":208,"question":"What is the tune of the song called","option1":"Ragam","option2":"Taal","option3":"Taalam","option4":"Swara","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Ragam","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":209,"question":"Shankar Mahadevan teamed up with which famous Indian Poet for the album\"Breathless\"","option1":"Sameer","option2":"Harvanshrai Bacchan","option3":"Mehboob","option4":"Jaaved Akhtar","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Jaaved Akhtar","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":210,"question":"Which is an Indian string instrument","option1":"Guitar","option2":"Piano","option3":"Violin","option4":"Sitar","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Sitar","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":211,"question":"19   ……. = 42","option1":"23","option2":"61","option3":"0","option4":"42","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"23","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":212,"question":"What is the symbol of pi?","option1":"€","option2":" ?","option3":"?","option4":"?","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":" ?","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":213,"question":" Arrange the numbers in ascending order: 36, 12, 29, 21, 7.","option1":"36, 29, 21, 12, 7","option2":"36, 29, 7, 21, 12 ","option3":" 7, 12, 21, 29, 36 ","option4":" D. None of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":" 7, 12, 21, 29, 36 ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":214,"question":"Which is the highest voice or tone in which one is allowed to sing","option1":"As high as the voice of all popular singers","option2":"Level 3","option3":"Level 4","option4":"There are no limits","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"There are no limits","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":215,"question":"What is the greatest two digit number?","option1":"10","option2":"90","option3":"11","option4":"99","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"99","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":216,"question":"Find the value of x; if x = (2 × 3)   11.","option1":"55","option2":"192","option3":"17","option4":"66","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"17","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":217,"question":"How many sounds does Tabla produces","option1":"10","option2":"12","option3":"8","option4":"17","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"12","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":218,"question":"What is 1000 × 1 equal to?","option1":"1","option2":"1000","option3":"0","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1000","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":219,"question":"When was Lata Mangeshkar  awarded the Padma Bhushan","option1":"1969","option2":"1948","option3":"1935","option4":"2001","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"1969","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":220,"question":"Which of the following musical instruments is of Indian origin","option1":"Guitar","option2":"Drums","option3":"Piano","option4":"Flute","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Flute","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":221,"question":"The largest number of six digits is ….. .","option1":"9,99,999","option2":"1,00,000","option3":"1,11,111","option4":"1,11,000","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"9,99,999","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":222,"question":"Who sang the theme tune to the Bond film Tomorrow Never Dies","option1":"Ustad Ali Khan","option2":"Sheryl Crow","option3":"Hank Marvin","option4":"Belinda Carlisle","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Sheryl Crow","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":223,"question":"A number is divisible by 5 if its unit digit is ………………… .","option1":"2 or 0","option2":"10 or 0","option3":"0 or 5","option4":" None of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"0 or 5","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":224,"question":"In 24,673 ; the place-value of 6 is ….. .","option1":"700","option2":"600","option3":"10","option4":"100","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"600","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":225,"question":"50 times 5 is equal to","option1":"2500","option2":"500","option3":"505","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"None of these ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":226,"question":"How many digits are there in 1000?","option1":"One digit","option2":"Two digits  ","option3":"Three digit","option4":"Four digit","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"Four digit","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":227,"question":"1 dime = …….. dollar","option1":"0.20","option2":"10","option3":"0.10","option4":"0.01","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"0.10","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":228,"question":"How many factors are there in 71?","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":" None of these.","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"2","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":229,"question":"What country is the singer The Weekend originally from","option1":"Canada","option2":"Kenia","option3":"USA","option4":"Mexica","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Canada","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":230,"question":"2 is a …………… number.","option1":"Odd","option2":"Prime ","option3":"Composite","option4":"Non of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"Prime ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":232,"question":"Who is Calvin Broadus","option1":"Wiz Khalifa","option2":"Dr Dre","option3":"Snoop Dogg","option4":"Drake","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Snoop Dogg","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":233,"question":"What is the sum of one digit prime numbers?","option1":"11","option2":"13","option3":"15","option4":"17","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"17","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":234,"question":"The way is a 2013 song released by which artist","option1":"Rihanna","option2":"Selena Gomez","option3":"Shakira","option4":"Ariana Grande","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Ariana Grande","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":235,"question":"Name a triangle whose two angles are equal.","option1":"Right angle triangle.","option2":"Isosceles triangle.","option3":"Scalene triangle.","option4":"None of these.","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"Isosceles triangle.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":236,"question":"Which malayalee won the National Award for Best Art Director of 2007","option1":"Sabu Cyril","option2":"The garden Tarani","option3":"Rajeevan","option4":"ArtistNmboodiri","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Sabu Cyril","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":237,"question":"Average of three person’s age is 9 years. Find the sum of there age.","option1":"18","option2":"21","option3":"24","option4":"27","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"27","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":238,"question":"This film is the only Bharathan film to feature mythology","option1":"I am Gandharvan","option2":"Vaishali","option3":"Just Listen","option4":"Charm","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Vaishali","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":239,"question":" What are the integer solutions of the inequality |x| < 2?","option1":"1, 0, and –1 ","option2":" 2, 1, 0, –1, and –2 ","option3":"2","option4":"2 and –2","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1, 0, and –1 ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":240,"question":"What is the opposite of 6?","option1":"6","option2":"5","option3":"4","option4":"-6","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"-6","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":241,"question":"Who directed the 1994 National Award winning film\"Parinayam\"for best social relevance\n","option1":"Hariharan","option2":"Adoor Gopalakrishnan","option3":"Jayaraj","option4":"Fassil","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Hariharan","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":243,"question":"The first Indian movie submitted for Oscar","option1":"The guide","option2":"Mother India","option3":"Madhumati","option4":"Amrapali","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Mother India","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":244,"question":"What is the value of a^0?","option1":"a","option2":"-1","option3":"0","option4":"1","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":245,"question":"The first Indian sound film was","option1":"Alam Ara","option2":"Raja Harishchandra","option3":"Kishan Kanya","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Alam Ara","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":246,"question":"Last film directed by Satyajit Ray","option1":"Agantuk","option2":"Bala","option3":"Pikoo","option4":"Jana Aranya","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Agantuk","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":247,"question":"How many cents is equal to $ ¼?","option1":"15","option2":"20","option3":"25","option4":"30","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"25","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":248,"question":"How many months are equal to 45 days?","option1":"1 ½ months.","option2":" 1 ¼ months","option3":"¼ months.","option4":"2 ¼ months months","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1 ½ months.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":250,"question":"How many diagonals are there in a quadrilateral?","option1":"2","option2":"3","option3":"4","option4":"No diagonals.","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"2","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":252,"question":"Which bollywood film with highest number of songs","option1":"Neel Kamal","option2":"Indra Sabha","option3":"Alam Ara","option4":"Kishan Kanaya","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Indra Sabha","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":253,"question":"Speed of a car is 60 km/hr. Distance covered in 1 ¼ hours is ","option1":"60 km","option2":"65 km","option3":"70 km","option4":"75 km","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"75 km","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":254,"question":"Which unit is used to measure length and breadth?","option1":"Scale.","option2":" Meter.","option3":"Liter","option4":"gram","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":" Meter.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":255,"question":"First 3 D animation film from India is","option1":"Roadside Romeo","option2":"Ghayab Aaya","option3":"Hanuman","option4":"Bal Ganesh","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Roadside Romeo","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":257,"question":"Who play the leading role in the film Raja Harishchandra","option1":"Vithal","option2":"Prithviraj Kapoor","option3":"DD Dabke","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"DD Dabke","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":259,"question":"How many movies are made by Dadasaheb Phalke","option1":"13","option2":"57","option3":"101","option4":"95","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":260,"question":"Who join the Cannes Film Festival,2013 as Jury member","option1":"Vidya Balan","option2":"Amitabh Bachchan ","option3":"Sonam Kapoor","option4":"Aishwarya Rai","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Vidya Balan","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":261,"question":" If David’s age is 27 years old in 2011. What was his age in 2003?","option1":"17 years","option2":"37 years","option3":" 20 years","option4":"19 years","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"19 years","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":262,"question":" What is the remainder of 21 divided by 7?","option1":"21","option2":"7","option3":"1","option4":"Non of these","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"Non of these","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":263,"question":"Which  one is the first Bollywood film of Sridevi","option1":"Julie","option2":"Himmatwala","option3":"Sadma","option4":"Solva Sawan","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Solva Sawan","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":264,"question":"Which Hindi movie got first National Award","option1":"Shree 420","option2":"Jagriti","option3":"Mizra Ghalib","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Mizra Ghalib","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":265,"question":"Who was known as the first lady of Indian cinema","option1":"Meena Kumari","option2":"Devika Rani Chaudhuri","option3":"Suraiya","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Devika Rani Chaudhuri","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":266,"question":"What is the square of 15?","option1":"15","option2":"30","option3":"225","option4":"252","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"225","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":267,"question":"What is the reciprocal of 17/15?","option1":"1.13","option2":"15/17","option3":" 17/15","option4":"30/34","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"15/17","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":268,"question":"What was the first Cinemascope film","option1":"Kagaz Ke Phool","option2":"Deewana","option3":"Darr","option4":"Bazigar","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Kagaz Ke Phool","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":""},{"id":269,"question":"Film and Television Institute of India is situated at","option1":"Delhi","option2":"Banglore","option3":"Pune","option4":"Chennai","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Movies","answer":"Pune","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":270,"question":" The square root of 0.0081 is ………… .","option1":"0.09","option2":"0.9","option3":" 0.91","option4":"0.009","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"0.09","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":271,"question":"10-2 means …………. .","option1":"milli","option2":"centi","option3":" micro","option4":"deci","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"centi","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":272,"question":"The cube root of 1331 is ………… .","option1":"11","option2":"13","option3":"19","option4":"17","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"11","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":273,"question":" All natural numbers and 0 are called the ……………….. numbers","option1":"whole","option2":"prime","option3":"integer","option4":" rational","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"whole","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":274,"question":"In which year did Badminton become an Olympic sport","option1":"1995","option2":"1976","option3":"1992","option4":"1990","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"1992","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":275,"question":"Each game is played up to how many points","option1":"21","option2":"14","option3":"27","option4":"10","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"21","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":276,"question":"The least number of five digits which is completely divisible by 39, is ………. .","option1":"10101","option2":"10062","option3":"10016","option4":"10023","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"10023","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":277,"question":"What is 121 times 11?","option1":"1331","option2":"1313","option3":"1133","option4":"1333","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1331","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":278,"question":"The interval  between games of a match in badminton cannot exceed how many minutes","option1":"Five","option2":"One","option3":"Two","option4":"One","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Two","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":279,"question":"10001 – 101 = ?","option1":"9900","option2":"9000","option3":"9089","option4":"9989","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"9900","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":280,"question":"A number is greater than 3 but less than 8. Also the number is greater than 6 but less than 10. What is the number?","option1":"5","option2":"6","option3":"7","option4":"8","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"7","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":281,"question":"In the following series a wrong number is given. Find out that number.\n4, 5, 10, 18, 34, 59, 95","option1":"5","option2":"10","option3":"18","option4":"34","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"10","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":282,"question":"How many times can a player strike a shuttlecock before it flies over the net","option1":"Twice","option2":"Once","option3":"Thrice","option4":"5 Times","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Once","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":283,"question":"The sum of squares of two numbers is 80 and the square of difference between the two numbers is 36. Find the product of two numbers","option1":"11","option2":"22","option3":"33","option4":"26","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"22","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":285,"question":"How many sides are there in a nonagon?","option1":"3","option2":"5","option3":"7","option4":"9","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"9","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":286,"question":"What kind of number is 37?","option1":"Odd.","option2":"Prime.","option3":"Both a and b.","option4":" None of these.","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"Both a and b.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":287,"question":"The number which is neither prime nor composite is ……. .","option1":"0","option2":"1","option3":"3","option4":"2","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"1","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":289,"question":"Take out the wrong number from the given series.\n3, 4, 9, 33, 136, 685, 4116 ","option1":"3","option2":"33","option3":"9","option4":"136","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"9","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":290,"question":". Which number is missing? 1, 9, 25, 49, (?)","option1":"234","option2":"99","option3":"81","option4":"77","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"81","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":291,"question":" If 6 is 50percentage of a number, what is the number?","option1":"10","option2":"12","option3":"24","option4":"3","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"12","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":292,"question":"561204 × 58 = ? × 55555","option1":"456","option2":"432","option3":"5432","option4":"586","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"586","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"sarathps@quizapp.com"},{"id":293,"question":"Which of the famous personalities play badminton","option1":"Diego Maradonna","option2":"Paul Newman","option3":"Nick Faldo","option4":"All of them","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"All of them","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":294,"question":"The headquarters of the Badminton World Federation were relocated to which country in 2005","option1":"Malaysia","option2":"Canada","option3":"Thailand","option4":"Kolombia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Malaysia","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":295,"question":"What score has been achieved in badminton to win the game","option1":"25","option2":"15","option3":"21","option4":"28","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"21","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":296,"question":"The Bath Badminton club was established in ","option1":"1905","option2":"1874","option3":"1877","option4":"1895","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"1877","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":297,"question":"The Badminton World Cup was last held in ","option1":"2009","option2":"2003","option3":"1999","option4":"2006","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"2006","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":298,"question":"In the third game of a badminton match,players change ends when a side first scores how many points","option1":"11","option2":"15","option3":"10","option4":"20","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"11","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":299,"question":"Which of these badminton strokes travel the slowest","option1":"Drive","option2":"Clear","option3":"Smash","option4":"Drop","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Drop","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":300,"question":"Which of these is not a usually stroke for defending a smash","option1":"Lift","option2":"Block","option3":"Drive","option4":"Clear","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Clear","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":301,"question":"Which of the following strokes is not used in Badminton","option1":"the clear","option2":"the smash","option3":"the drop","option4":"the putt","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"the putt","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":302,"question":"Which Badminton player won the Indian Open Grand Prix Gold championship in 2014","option1":"Misha Zilberman","option2":"Xue Song","option3":"Kashyap Parupalli","option4":"Brice Leverdez","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Xue Song","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":303,"question":"Who is the youngest Badminton player to represent India at championships","option1":"Vaishnavi Reddy","option2":"Gayatri Gopichand","option3":"Radhika Menon","option4":"Jwala Gutta","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Gayatri Gopichand","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":304,"question":"What color cards do the referees carry in a football match","option1":"Red and Yellow","option2":"Black and White","option3":"Red and Green","option4":"Yellow and Green","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Red and Yellow","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":305,"question":"What is the main color of Brazils national team shirt ","option1":"Red","option2":"Black","option3":"Pink","option4":"Yellow","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Yellow","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":306,"question":"What is the usual length of time allowed for half time interval in a football match","option1":"10 minutes","option2":"15 minutes","option3":"1 hour","option4":"25 minutes","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"15 minutes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":307,"question":"A spot-kick is taken from where","option1":"The centre spot","option2":"The penalty spot","option3":"The Ink spot","option4":"On the spot","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"The penalty spot","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":308,"question":"How many minutes are usually played in a football match","option1":"30","option2":"45","option3":"90","option4":"200","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"90","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":309,"question":"Real Madrid plays football in which European country","option1":"Germany","option2":"Scotland","option3":"Spain","option4":"Italy","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Spain","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"keerthi@quizapp.com"},{"id":315,"question":"Find the sum of 111   222   333","option1":"700","option2":"666","option3":"10","option4":"100","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Maths","answer":"666","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":316,"question":"What does LBW stand for? ","option1":"Long ball wide","option2":"Leg beyond width","option3":"Leg before wicket","option4":"Lol bout to win","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Leg before wicket","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":317,"question":"Who did England beat in the final of 2019 World Cup? ","option1":"India","option2":"Srilanka ","option3":"Australia","option4":"New Zealand","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"New Zealand","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":318,"question":"Which is these places is cricket not a popular sport? ","option1":"India","option2":"Pakistan","option3":"Myanmar","option4":"New Zealand","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Myanmar","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":319,"question":"How long does test cricket usually go on for? ","option1":"3 to 5 days","option2":"90 minutes","option3":"6 hours","option4":"Over a week","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"3 to 5 days","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":320,"question":"How do you win at cricket? ","option1":"By scoring most goals","option2":"By scoring most runs and losing least wickets","option3":"By losing all your wickets","option4":"By cheating","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"By scoring most runs and losing least wickets","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":321,"question":"What do you call a referee in cricket? ","option1":"Vampire","option2":"Umpire","option3":"Keeper","option4":"Batsman","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Umpire","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":322,"question":"What is a cricket ball made of? ","option1":"Cork, string and leather","option2":"Rubber, plastic and gum","option3":"Wood, plastic and cardboard","option4":"Dog hair, spam and foil","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Cork, string and leather","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":323,"question":"Who is the captain of England cricket team 2019? ","option1":"MS dhoni","option2":"Virat kohli","option3":"Alistair Cook","option4":"Joe root","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Joe root","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":324,"question":"Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in first class cricket? ","option1":"Sachin Tendulkar","option2":"Brian Lara","option3":"Yuvaraj Singh","option4":"Lane Hutton ","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Brian Lara","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":325,"question":"Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in ODI cricket? ","option1":"Sachin Tendulkar","option2":"Brian Lara","option3":"Rohit Sharma","option4":"Martin Guptill","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Rohit Sharma","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":326,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most centuries in first class cricket? ","option1":"Chris Gayle ","option2":"Virat kohli","option3":"Sachin Tendulkar","option4":"Jack Hobbs","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Jack Hobbs","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":327,"question":"Which cricketer had scored fastest century in ODI cricket? ","option1":"Chris Gayle","option2":"Rohit Sharma","option3":"Yuvaraj Singh","option4":"AB de Velliers","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"AB de Velliers","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":328,"question":"Which cricketer has taken most catches in ODI cricket? ","option1":"Suresh Raina ","option2":"Virat Kohli","option3":"Mahela Jayavardene","option4":"MS Dhoni","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Mahela Jayavardene","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":329,"question":"Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in test cricket? ","option1":"Brain Lara","option2":"Sachin Tendulkar","option3":"MS Dhoni","option4":"Suresh Raina","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Brain Lara","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":330,"question":"Which cricketer had scored fastest century in test cricket? ","option1":"Brendon Mccullum","option2":"Virat Kohli","option3":"Sachin Tendulkar","option4":"MS Dhoni","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Brendon Mccullum","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":331,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most runs in a Test match?","option1":" Graham Gooch     ","option2":"Sunil Gavaskar","option3":"Don Bradman","option4":"Brian Lara","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":" Graham Gooch     ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":332,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most runs in a Test series?","option1":"Sunil Gavaskar","option2":"Don Bradman","option3":"Kumar Sangakkara","option4":"Vivian Richards","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Don Bradman","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":333,"question":"Which cricketer had scored most test runs in a calendar year? \n \n\n","option1":"Brain Lara","option2":" Rahul Dravid","option3":" Steve Waugh","option4":"Mohamed Yusuf","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Mohamed Yusuf","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":334,"question":" First Englishman who had taken hat-trick wicket in Test cricket?\n\n\n\n","option1":"Billy Bates","option2":"Jack Hearne","option3":"Johnny Briggs","option4":"George Lehmann","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Billy Bates","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":335,"question":"Which player had taken first hat-trick in the history of Test cricket?\n","option1":"Fred Spofforth (Australia)  ","option2":"George Lehmann (England) ","option3":"Johnny Briggs (England)","option4":"Jack Hearne (England)","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Fred Spofforth (Australia)  ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":336,"question":" How many teams are participating in the ICC World Cup 2019?","option1":"8","option2":"9","option3":"10","option4":"12","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"10","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":337,"question":"Which cricket team has won most ICC Cricket World Cup titles? ","option1":"India","option2":"England","option3":"Australia","option4":"New Zealand","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Australia","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":338,"question":"Which of the following country did not won the ICC Cricket World Cup (50 over format) title so far?","option1":"England","option2":"New Zealand","option3":"South Africa","option4":"All of the above","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"All of the above","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":339,"question":"Which of the following Indian player have got first “Man of the Tournament” Award in the ICC Cricket World Cup?","option1":"Sachin Tendulkar","option2":"Yuvraj Singh","option3":"MS Dhoni","option4":"Suresh Raina","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Sachin Tendulkar","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":340,"question":"When was first ICC cricket World Cup started?","option1":"1972           ","option2":"1979","option3":"1985","option4":"1975","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"1975","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":341,"question":"Which of the following statement is NOT correct about the ICC cricket World Cup?","option1":"It is played after the gap of every 4 years.        ","option2":"The “Man of the Match” award in the ICC cricket World Cup was started in the 1992.","option3":"Pakistan and Sri Lanka are the other two countries that have won the World Cup in 1992 and 1996 respectively.","option4":"England is the only country which lost 2 ICC World Cup finals.","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"The “Man of the Match” award in the ICC cricket World Cup was started in the 1992.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":342,"question":"Who is the father of cricket?\n","option1":"W. G. Grace","option2":"Sachin Tendulkar","option3":"MS Dhoni","option4":"Brian Lara","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"W. G. Grace","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":343,"question":"Who invented cricket? ","option1":"New Zealand","option2":"India","option3":"South England","option4":"West indies","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"South England","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":344,"question":"When was the first Test match played?","option1":"1877","option2":"1849","option3":"1928","option4":"1972","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"1877","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":345,"question":"is the father of cricket?\nWhich nation lost the most games in the first eight World Cups?","option1":"India","option2":"West Indies","option3":"Zimbabwe ","option4":"Australia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Zimbabwe ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":346,"question":"Which of the following country won Football world Cup maximum times?\n\n\n\n\n\n \n\n","option1":"Germany","option2":"Italy","option3":"Argentina","option4":"Brazil","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Brazil","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":347,"question":"Who among the following player scores highest number of goals in Footbal World Cup?","option1":"Pele","option2":"Miroslave Klose","option3":"Meradona","option4":"Jurgen Klinsmann","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Miroslave Klose","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":348,"question":"Which of the following term is recognised as an early form of football by FIFA?","option1":"kemari","option2":"Episkyros","option3":"Cuju","option4":"Inuit","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Episkyros","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":349,"question":"When was the first FIFA World Cup inaugurated?","option1":"1930","option2":"1931","option3":"1932","option4":"1933","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"1930","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":350,"question":"Which of following team do not play in stripes?","option1":"Southampton","option2":"New castle","option3":"Tottenham Hotspur","option4":"Lincoln City","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Tottenham Hotspur","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":351,"question":"Which of the following country hosted the first Football World Cup?","option1":"America","option2":"Argentina","option3":"Brazil","option4":"Uruguay","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Uruguay","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":352,"question":"Which country became the first nation to win the Football World Cup?","option1":"Uruguay","option2":"Germany","option3":"Argentina","option4":"Portugal","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Uruguay","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":353,"question":"When was first official international football match was played?","option1":"1872","option2":"1871","option3":"1869","option4":"1870","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"1872","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":354,"question":"Who among the following scored the first goal in World Cup history?","option1":"Bert Patenaude   ","option2":"Lucien Laurent","option3":"Johino","option4":"Pele","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Lucien Laurent","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":355,"question":"Who among the following achieved the first World Cup hat-trick?","option1":"Pele ","option2":"Johino","option3":" Bert Patenaude   ","option4":"Lucien Laurent","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":" Bert Patenaude   ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":356,"question":"Which badminton player won the Indian Open Grand Prix Gold championship in 2014?","option1":" Misha Zilberman","option2":"Xue Song","option3":"Kashyap Parupalli","option4":"Brice Leverdez","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Xue Song","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":357,"question":" In which stadium India Open Grand Prix Gold tournament held?","option1":"Babu Banarasi Das Indoor Stadium  ","option2":"Rajib Gandhi Indoor Stadium","option3":"Sports Authority of India Complex","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Babu Banarasi Das Indoor Stadium  ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":358,"question":"Which player won the women’s singles title at India Open Super Series Badminton tournament 2015?","option1":"Saina Nehwal","option2":" Jwala Gutta  ","option3":"Yihan Wang","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Saina Nehwal","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":359,"question":"Who is the youngest badminton player to represent India at championships?","option1":"Vaishnav Reddy","option2":" Gayatri Gopichand  ","option3":"Radhika Menon","option4":"Jwala Gutta","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":" Gayatri Gopichand  ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":360,"question":"Who became the first Indian to win the All England Open Championship in 1980?","option1":"Prakash Padukone","option2":"Chetan Anand","option3":"Rajeev Bagga","option4":"Pranav Chopra","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Prakash Padukone","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":361,"question":"Who was the first Indian badminton player to hold number one rank in World rankings?","option1":" Manu Attri ","option2":"Chetan Anand","option3":"Prakash Padukone","option4":"None of these","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Prakash Padukone","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":362,"question":"Who is the first Indian badminton player to won the Gold Medal at the Commonwealth Games in Australia?","option1":"Prakash Padukone","option2":"Ajay Jayaram","option3":"Pullela Gopichand","option4":"Syed Modi","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Syed Modi","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":363,"question":"Who won the All England Open Championship in 2001?","option1":"Gurusai Dutt  ","option2":"Pullela Gopichand","option3":"Prakash Padukone","option4":"Kidambi Srikanth","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"Pullela Gopichand","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":364,"question":"The female badminton player became the youngest Padma Shri awardee in 2015. Who is she? ","option1":"PV Sindhu","option2":"Jwala Gutta","option3":"Saina Nehwal","option4":"None of these ","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Badminton","answer":"PV Sindhu","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":365,"question":"Which one of the following remains constant while throwing a ball upward?","option1":"Velocity","option2":"Displacement","option3":"Acceleration","option4":"Kinetic energy","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Acceleration","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":366,"question":"Which one among the following radiations carries maximum energy?","option1":"Gama rays","option2":"X-rays","option3":"Infra red rays","option4":"Ultraviolet rays","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Gama rays","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":367,"question":"Which one of the following is the unit of activity of a radioactive source?","option1":"Siemes","option2":"Lux","option3":"Tesla","option4":"Becquerrel","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Becquerrel","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":368,"question":"Which one of the following common devices works on the basis of the principle of mutual induction?","option1":"LED","option2":"Transformer","option3":"Photodiode","option4":"ube light","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Transformer","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":369,"question":"Oil or soap film when in daylight appears coloured because of","option1":"Reflection","option2":"Interference","option3":"Refraction","option4":"Surface energy","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Interference","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":370,"question":"A woman’s voice is shriller than man’s voice due ","option1":"Lower frequency","option2":"Higher frequency","option3":"Weak vocal chords","option4":"Higher amplitude","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Higher frequency","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":371,"question":"Which one of the following is used as a moderator in nuclear reactor","option1":"Radium","option2":"Graphite","option3":"Thorium","option4":"Ordinary water","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Graphite","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":372,"question":"Recording of sound on tapes was first invented by","option1":"Fleming","option2":"Ampere","option3":"Poulsen","option4":"Becquerrel","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Poulsen","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":373,"question":"Which one of the following would be most powerful electro magnet?","option1":"Soft iron","option2":"Steel","option3":"Copper","option4":"Air","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Soft iron","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":374,"question":"Production of beats is a result of the phenomenon of","option1":"Reflection","option2":"Resonance","option3":"Interference","option4":"Superposition","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Interference","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":375,"question":"Supersonic plane fly with the speed","option1":"less than the speed of sound","option2":"of sound","option3":"of light","option4":"greater than the speed of sound","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"greater than the speed of sound","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":376,"question":"Mach number is used in connection with the speed of","option1":"sound","option2":"aircraft","option3":"spacecraft","option4":"ships","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"aircraft","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":377,"question":"On a stationary sail boat, air is blown from a fan attached to the boat. The boat","option1":"moves in opposite direction in which the air is blown","option2":"Does not move","option3":"moves in the same direction in which air blows","option4":"spins around","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Does not move","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":378,"question":"Atmospheric pressure is measured by","option1":"Tonometer","option2":"Pyrometer","option3":"Barometer","option4":"Thermometer","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Barometer","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":379,"question":"Sudden fall in barometer is indication of","option1":"Storm","option2":"Rain","option3":"Tide","option4":"Clear weather","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Storm","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":380,"question":"Which is true","option1":"In a static liquid at same horizontal level, pressure is more at centre","option2":"In a static liquid at same horizontal level, pressure is less at centre.","option3":"In a static liquid at same horizontal level, pressure is same at all points","option4":"In a static liquid at same horizontal level, pressure is different at all points","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"In a static liquid at same horizontal level, pressure is same at all points","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":381,"question":"Force of attraction between the molecules of different substances is called","option1":"Surface tension","option2":"Cohensive force","option3":"Adhesive force","option4":"None of above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Adhesive force","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":382,"question":"Which of the following measurements is not a unit of distance?","option1":"Ammeter","option2":"Cubit","option3":"Parsec","option4":"angstrom","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Ammeter","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":384,"question":"Pure water freezes at what temperature?","option1":"47 F","option2":"32 F","option3":"0 F","option4":"19 F","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"32 F","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":385,"question":"Which vitamin is abundant in citrus fruits?","option1":"Vitamin A","option2":"Vitamin B","option3":"Vitamin C","option4":"Vitamin D","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Vitamin C","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":386,"question":"Which one is a scalar quantity?","option1":"Acceleration","option2":"Displacement","option3":"Speed","option4":"Velocity","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Speed","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":387,"question":"What is the rate of acceleration of gravity?","option1":"10 m/s/s","option2":"9.8 m/s/s","option3":"6.8 m/s/s","option4":"7.8 m/s/s","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"9.8 m/s/s","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":388,"question":"Rainbow is due to","option1":"absorption of sunlight in minute water droplets","option2":"diffusion of sunlight through water droplets","option3":"ionisation of water deposits","option4":"refraction and reflection of sunlight by water droplets","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"refraction and reflection of sunlight by water droplets","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":389,"question":"Stars which appear single to the naked eye but are double when seen through a telescope are","option1":"novas and supernovas","option2":"binaries","option3":"asteroids","option4":"quasars","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"binaries","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":390,"question":"The working principle of a washing machine is","option1":"reverse osmosis","option2":"diffusion","option3":"centrifugation","option4":"dialysis","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"centrifugation","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":391,"question":"Nuclear sizes are expressed in a unit named","option1":"Fermi","option2":"Angstrom","option3":"Newton","option4":"Tesla","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"Fermi","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":395,"question":"How many teams have won the World Cup since its inception in 1930?","option1":"8","option2":"7","option3":"5","option4":"4","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"8","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":396,"question":"Brazil has the most number of World Cup titles to its credit. How many times has it won the World Cup so far?","option1":"5","option2":"4","option3":"6","option4":"7","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Physics","answer":"5","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":397,"question":"In which year was the football World Cup held for the first time?","option1":"1928","option2":"1930","option3":"1924","option4":"1932","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"1930","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":398,"question":"Which country won the first football World Cup?","option1":"Brazil","option2":"Germany","option3":"Uruguay","option4":"Argentina","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Uruguay","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":399,"question":"Paul, a marine creature, which supposedly predicted the outcome of many matches in World Cup 2010 was a/an","option1":"Jelly fish","option2":"Walrus","option3":"Octopus","option4":"Seal","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Octopus","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":400,"question":"In which country is FIFA World Cup 2018 scheduled to be played?","option1":"Qatar","option2":"Russia","option3":"South Korea","option4":"France","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Russia","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":401,"question":"To which country does the famous player Ronaldo, who held the record for most number of World Cup goals, belong?","option1":"France","option2":"Spain","option3":"Portugal","option4":"Brazil","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Brazil","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":402,"question":" In which country are the headquarters of FIFA (International Federation of Association Football) located?","option1":"Switzerland","option2":"Brazil","option3":"France","option4":"The Netherlands","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Switzerland","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":403,"question":"Who has the record for scoring the most goals in World Cup history?","option1":"Ronaldo","option2":"Diego Maradona","option3":"Miroslav Klose","option4":"Lionel Messi","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Miroslav Klose","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":404,"question":"Which trophy was awarded to the winners of World Cup tournament until 1970?","option1":"Arsenal Trophy","option2":"Heisman Trophy","option3":"Grondona Cup","option4":"Jules Rimet Trophy","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Jules Rimet Trophy","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":405,"question":"What kind of animal was Zabivaka, the mascot for FIFA World Cup 2018?","option1":"Tiger","option2":"Cat","option3":"Polar Bear","option4":"Wolf","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Wolf","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":406,"question":"Who of the following was awarded the Golden Ball or the Best Player Award at the 2018 FIFA World Cup?","option1":"Luka Modric","option2":"Harry Kane","option3":"Romelu Lukaku","option4":"Cristiano Ronaldo","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Luka Modric","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":407,"question":"In which year did France win the World Cup earlier?","option1":"1994","option2":"1998","option3":"2002","option4":"2004","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"1998","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":408,"question":"Thibaut Courtois who was awarded the Golden Glove award for the best goalkeeper at the World Cup 2018 is from which country?","option1":"Croatia","option2":"France","option3":"England","option4":"Belgium","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Belgium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":409,"question":"Who was the captain of the 2018 World Cup winning team of France?","option1":"Hugo Lloris","option2":"Paul Pogba","option3":"Kylian Mbappe","option4":"Antoinne Griezmann","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Hugo Lloris","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":410,"question":"From which confederation did the most number of teams qualify for the World Cup 2018 final 32?","option1":"CONCACAF","option2":"CONMEBOL","option3":"UEFA","option4":"CAF","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"UEFA","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":411,"question":"Who of the following players scored a hat-trick of goals in the World Cup 2018?","option1":"Cristiano Ronaldo","option2":"Harry Kane","option3":"Both (a) and (b)","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Both (a) and (b)","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":412,"question":"Luzhniki Stadium which hosted the opening and closing ceremonies in World Cup 2018 is located in which city?","option1":"Moscow","option2":"Volgograd","option3":"Saint Petersburg","option4":"Sochi","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Moscow","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":413,"question":"Which team was awarded the FIFA Fair Play Award at the World Cup 2018 tournament?","option1":"England","option2":"Japan","option3":"Spain","option4":"Croatia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Spain","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":414,"question":"Which of the following was the official song of the FIFA World Cup 2018?","option1":"All In One Rhythm","option2":"Live it up","option3":"Go for it","option4":"Football in space","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Live it up","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":415,"question":"What name has been given to the special font typeface designed by Brandia Central for writing the official logo Russia 2018 of FIFA World Cup 2018?","option1":"Kremlin","option2":"Molot","option3":"Troika","option4":"Dusha","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Dusha","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":416,"question":"What name was given to the football used for the final match between France and Croatia at the FIFA World Cup 2018?","option1":"Telstar Elast","option2":"Telstar Durlast","option3":"Telstar Mechta","option4":"Telstar Plast","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Telstar Mechta","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":417,"question":"Which team scored the highest number of goals at the FIFA World Cup 2018?","option1":"Belgium","option2":"France","option3":"England","option4":"Croatia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Belgium","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":418,"question":"Who of the following was the manager of the French team at the FIFA World Cup 2018 as well as the captain of the team which won the World Cup in 1998?","option1":"Ricardo Gareca","option2":"Didier Deschamps","option3":"Fernando Hierro","option4":"Juan Carlo Osorio","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Didier Deschamps","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":419,"question":"Who was selected for the Man of the Match Award in the finals of World Cup 2018?","option1":"Antoine Griezman","option2":"Kylian Mbappe","option3":"Paul Pogba","option4":"Raphael Varane","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Antoine Griezman","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":420,"question":"How much was the prize money awarded to the World Cup winning team France at the tournament?","option1":"22 million dollars","option2":"26 million dollars","option3":"32 million dollars","option4":"38 million dollars","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"38 million dollars","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":421,"question":"Who of the following became the second teenager in the history of World Cup football to score a goal in the finals?","option1":"Antoine Griezman","option2":"Kylian Mbappe","option3":"Paul Pogba","option4":"Raphael Varane","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Kylian Mbappe","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":422,"question":"What kind of animal was Fuleco, the mascot for FIFA World Cup 2014?","option1":"Giant Anteater","option2":"Alpaca","option3":"Armadillo","option4":"Otter","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Armadillo","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":423,"question":"Who of the following was awarded the Golden Ball or the Best Player Award at the 2014 FIFA World Cup?","option1":"Paul Pogba","option2":"Lionel Messi","option3":"Neymar","option4":"Mario Gotze","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Lionel Messi","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":424,"question":"Who of the following was awarded the Golden Boot Award for most goals in the tournament of 2014?","option1":"Miroslave Klose","option2":"James Rodriguez","option3":"Thomas Muller","option4":"Neymar","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"James Rodriguez","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":425,"question":"Who was awarded the Golden Glove award for the best goalkeeper at the World Cup 2014?","option1":"Manuel Neuer","option2":"Tim Krul","option3":"Julio Cesar","option4":"Sergio Romero","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Manuel Neuer","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":426,"question":"Who scored the winning goal for Germany against Argentina in the finals of World Cup 2014?","option1":"Mario Gotze","option2":"Miroslave Klose","option3":"Mats Hummels","option4":"Thomas Muller","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Mario Gotze","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":427,"question":"How many countries played at the World Cup 2014 tournament?","option1":"36","option2":"32","option3":"28","option4":"30","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"32","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":428,"question":"Who was the captain of the 2014 World Cup winning team from Germany?","option1":"Philipp Lahm","option2":"Manuel Neuer","option3":"Miroslave Klose","option4":"Mats Hummels","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Philipp Lahm","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":429,"question":"How many teams from the Asian continent participated in the FIFA World Cup 2014 tournament?","option1":"Four","option2":"Two","option3":"One","option4":"Three","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Three","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":430,"question":"Who of the following players scored a hat-trick of goals in the World Cup 2014?","option1":"Thomas Muller","option2":"Xherdan Shaqiri","option3":"Both (a) and (b)","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Both (a) and (b)","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":431,"question":" At which of the following stadiums was the final match between Germany and Argentina played in World Cup 2014?","option1":"Mineirao","option2":"Maracana","option3":"Arena Castelao","option4":"Arena Da Amazonia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Maracana","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":432,"question":"Which team was awarded the FIFA Fair Play Award at the World Cup 2014 tournament?","option1":"Germany","option2":"Netherlands","option3":"Spain","option4":"Columbia","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Columbia","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":433,"question":"What was the slogan of the FIFA World Cup 2014?","option1":"All In One Rhythm","option2":"Celebrate Humanity","option3":"Football For Peace","option4":"A Time To Make Friends","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"All In One Rhythm","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":434,"question":"Who was selected for the Man of the Match Award in the finals of World Cup 2014?","option1":"Lionel Messi","option2":"Mario Gotze","option3":"Mats Hummels","option4":"Thomas Muller","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Football","answer":"Mario Gotze","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":435,"question":"Which cricketer had scored highest individual score in first-class cricket?","option1":"Don Bradman","option2":"Brian Lara","option3":"Lane Hutton","option4":"Gary Sobers","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Cricket","answer":"Brian Lara","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":445,"question":"Which among these is the highest governing body of Hockey?","option1":"International Hockey Federation","option2":"World Hockey Federation","option3":"Federation of International Hockey","option4":"International Hockey Association","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"International Hockey Federation","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":446,"question":"Total no. of players playing on the pitch in a hockey match is?","option1":"22","option2":"16","option3":"20","option4":"18","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"22","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":447,"question":"Which player is allowed to touch the ball with his feet during a Hockey match?","option1":"Goalkeeper","option2":"Defender","option3":"Centre-forward","option4":"Winger","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"Goalkeeper","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":448,"question":"The dimensions of a Hockey field are?","option1":"91.4m X 55m","option2":"92m X 55m","option3":"92.5m X 56m","option4":"91.4m X 56m","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"91.4m X 55m","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":449,"question":"What are the dimensions of the goal at each end of the hockey field?","option1":"2.14m X 3.66m","option2":"2.15m X 3.66m","option3":"2.15m X 3.7m","option4":"2.14m X 3.7m","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"2.14m X 3.66m","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":450,"question":"The distance between thepenalty spot and the goal is?","option1":"6yrds","option2":"5yrds","option3":"8yrds","option4":"7yrds","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"7yrds","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":451,"question":"The shooting circle in a Hockey field is?","option1":"16yrd from the baseline","option2":"18yrd from the baseline","option3":"17yrd from the baseline","option4":"15yrd from the baseline","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"16yrd from the baseline","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":452,"question":"15yrd from the baseline","option1":"5","option2":"7","option3":"9","option4":"No limits","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"No limits","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":453,"question":"No. of field empires in a match is?","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"2","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":454,"question":"Each half in a hockey game consist of?","option1":"30mins","option2":"35mins","option3":"40mins","option4":"45mins","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"35mins","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":455,"question":"How long is the half break between two halves of a hockey match?","option1":"5mins","option2":"10mins","option3":"12mins","option4":"15mins","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"5mins","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":456,"question":"When does a player go to the penalty box?","option1":"When he gets a yellow card","option2":"When he gets a no card","option3":"When he gets a green card","option4":"When he gets a red card","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"When he gets a yellow card","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":457,"question":"Who is regarded as the best player in history of the sport?","option1":"Dhyan Chand","option2":"Roop Singh","option3":"DhanrajPillay","option4":"Niraj Singh","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"Dhyan Chand","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":458,"question":"Which nation has been crowned as World Champions of Hockey four times?","option1":"India","option2":"Pakistan","option3":"Australia","option4":"Netherlands","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"Pakistan","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":459,"question":"When was India toop part in Olympics for the first time?","option1":"1926","option2":"1927","option3":"1928","option4":"1929","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"1928","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":460,"question":"2018 Hockey World Cup was be held in?","option1":"India","option2":"Pakistan","option3":"Australia","option4":"Netherlands","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"India","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":461,"question":"India has won the Hockey World Cup how many times?","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"1","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":462,"question":"Which nation has the most Olympic Gold Medals in Hockey with 8 medals?","option1":"India","option2":"Pakistan","option3":"Australia","option4":"Netherlands","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"India","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":463,"question":"When was India palyed first Hockey World Cup?","option1":"1970","option2":"1971","option3":"1972","option4":"1973","parentCategory":"Sports","category":"Hockey","answer":"1971","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":473,"question":"Which of the following musical instruments is of Indian origin?","option1":"Guitar","option2":"Drums","option3":"Piano","option4":"Flute","parentCategory":"Entertainment","category":"Music","answer":"Flute","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":474,"question":"In which form the chemical compound RDX is used?","option1":"As an composition","option2":"As an reactor","option3":"As an explosive","option4":"As an nuclear weapon","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"As an explosive","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":475,"question":"As a vegetable preservative poly______ foam is used.","option1":"Uthane","option2":"Uriathenes","option3":"Urathanes","option4":"Urethanes","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Urethanes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":476,"question":"Chemistry is a branch of science which can be used for providing the services to mankind. Comment on the statement.","option1":"True","option2":"False","option3":"May Be","option4":"Strongly not","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Strongly not","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":477,"question":"Bio-chemical compounds are used as....","option1":"Skin Treatments","option2":"Food preservatives","option3":"Cooking Oils","option4":"All of the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"All of the above","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":478,"question":"Detergent is defined as.....","option1":"A liquid surfactant","option2":"A liquid soluble","option3":" A liquid sovent","option4":"A liquid solution","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"A liquid surfactant","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":479,"question":"Which of the following compound is not used as an an alkali?","option1":"Sodium hydroxide","option2":"Potassium hydroxide","option3":"Nitrogen hydroxide","option4":"Carbon hydroxide","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Nitrogen hydroxide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":480,"question":"Define toxicity?","option1":"chemical reaction","option2":"A process used in the manufacturing of detergents","option3":" A harmful effect of soaps and detergents required to measure the effectiveness.","option4":"A process used in the manufacturing of soaps","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":" A harmful effect of soaps and detergents required to measure the effectiveness.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":481,"question":"Greatest number of Sweat glands are present in which part of the human body?","option1":"Forehead","option2":"Forearm","option3":"Palm of the hand","option4":"Back","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Palm of the hand","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":482,"question":"Vaccination was started by.......","option1":"Jonas E. Salk","option2":"Paul Muller","option3":"Edward Jenner","option4":"Robert Frost","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Edward Jenner","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":483,"question":"Proteins are made up of .......","option1":"Sugars","option2":"Amino acids","option3":"Fatty acids","option4":"Nucleic acids","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Amino acids","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":484,"question":"Mention the source of Liver, milk, egg yolk, fish liver oil?","option1":"Vitamin A","option2":"Vitamin B2","option3":"Vitamin D","option4":"Vitamin C","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Vitamin D","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":485,"question":"Which of the following name of scientist and their field of work is correctly matched?","option1":"DNA/Double helix: F. Crick J. Watson,","option2":"Modern classification of plants and animals based on a system: Harvey","option3":"Bacteria: Linnaeus","option4":"Blood travels in a continuous circuit: Leuwenhock","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"DNA/Double helix: F. Crick J. Watson,","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":486,"question":"Heart is made up of","option1":"Non-striated muscle","option2":"Cardiac muscle","option3":"Adipose tissue","option4":"Striated muscle","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Cardiac muscle","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":487,"question":"Hargobind Khorana had researched on .....","option1":"Synthesis of simple DNA","option2":"Understanding the genetic code","option3":"Reduction of mutation","option4":"Synthesis of RNA from bacterial cell","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Understanding the genetic code","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":488,"question":"Name the corona virus that kills human?","option1":"AIDS","option2":"FAIDS","option3":"SARS","option4":"HIV","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"SARS","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":489,"question":"In which part of the body digestion of protein starts?","option1":"Mouth","option2":"Duodenum","option3":"Stomach","option4":"Intestine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Stomach","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":490,"question":"Name the acid that is secreted in the stomach?","option1":"HCl","option2":"H2C03","option3":"H2S04","option4":"HNO3","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"HCl","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":491,"question":"Which vitamin is needed to prevent Xero-phthalmia?","option1":"A ","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"A ","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":492,"question":"Why the white blood corpuscles are popularly called \"soldiers of the body”?","option1":"March at a regular pace","option2":"Appear uniform","option3":"Defend the body","option4":"Disciplined","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Defend the body","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":493,"question":"Hepatitis is a general term for a disease that is caused by:","option1":"Viruses","option2":"Bacteria","option3":"Parasites","option4":"All the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Viruses","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":494,"question":"Which among the following is not an example of carbohydrate?","option1":"Maltose","option2":"Glycogen","option3":"Fructose","option4":"Glycine","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Glycine","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":495,"question":"Which one of the following is not correctly matched?","option1":"Haemoglobin: Skin","option2":"Vitamin C: Scurvy","option3":"Carbohydrate: Potato","option4":"Fat: Butter","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Haemoglobin: Skin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":496,"question":"Which is a communicable disease?","option1":"Asthma","option2":"Scurvy","option3":"Measles","option4":"Diabetes","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Measles","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":498,"question":"Which of the following has the highest protein content per gram?","option1":"Groundnut","option2":"Soyabean","option3":"Apple","option4":"Wheat","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Soyabean","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":499,"question":"Which of the following have Alpha-keratin as protein?","option1":"Skin","option2":"Blood","option3":"Eggs","option4":"Wool","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Wool","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":500,"question":"Mushrooms are/can be:  ","option1":" A variety of fungus","option2":"Fleshy, fruiting bodies of the fungus","option3":"Grown in small sheds or plots","option4":" All the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" All the above","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":501,"question":"Which of the following is not a primary food product?  ","option1":"Vegetables","option2":"Milk","option3":"Cereals","option4":"Fruits","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Cereals","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":502,"question":"Which of the following teeth of child (3-4 Years) is not a part of the milk teeth?","option1":"Incisors","option2":"Canines","option3":"Molars","option4":"Premolars","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Molars","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":503,"question":"Who said this statement? \"I flatter myself having discovered the method that nature employs to purify air.  It is vegetation.\"","option1":"Antonine Laurent Lavoisier","option2":" Joseph Priestley","option3":"Louis Pasteur","option4":"William Harvey","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":" Joseph Priestley","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":504,"question":"Why it is not advisable to sleep under a tree at night?","option1":"Release of less oxygen","option2":"Release of more oxygen","option3":"Release of carbon dioxide","option4":"Release of carbon monoxide","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Release of carbon dioxide","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":505,"question":"What is the averages rate of the heart beats (per minute) in an adult?","option1":"60","option2":"72","option3":"84","option4":"96","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"72","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":506,"question":"Which of the following is the volume of the urine produced in an adult human every 24 hours?","option1":"1 litre","option2":"3.0 litres","option3":"1.5 litres","option4":"5.0 litres","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"3.0 litres","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":507,"question":"Which of the following pigment causes eye colour of person (brown eyes, blue eyes or black eyes)?","option1":"Cornea","option2":"Choroid","option3":"Iris","option4":"Vitreous body","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Iris","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":508,"question":"Which of the following led to the expulsion of milk from the breast during suckling?\n\n","option1":"Prolactin","option2":"Estrogen and Progesterone","option3":"Oxytocin","option4":"Vasopressin","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Oxytocin","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":509,"question":"Where does fertilization occurs in the female?","option1":"Fallopian tube","option2":"Uterus","option3":"Cervix","option4":"Vagina","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"Fallopian tube","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":510,"question":"Which of the following is the universal recipient blood group?","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"AB","option4":"0","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Biology","answer":"AB","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":511,"question":"Who discovered cell in 1665?","option1":"Robert Hook","option2":"Robert Crook","option3":"David Thomson","option4":"Marie Francois","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Robert Hook","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":512,"question":"Name an Organelle which serves as a primary packaging area for molecules that will be distributed throughout the cell?","option1":"Mitochondria","option2":"Plastids","option3":"Golgi apparatus","option4":"Vacuole","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Golgi apparatus","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":513,"question":"Name the outer most boundary of the cell?","option1":"Plasma membrane","option2":"Cytoplasm","option3":"Nuclear membrane","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Plasma membrane","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":514,"question":"Name the process in which the ingestion of material by the cells is done through the plasma membrane?","option1":"Egestion","option2":"Diffusion","option3":"Osmosis","option4":"Endocytosis","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Endocytosis","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":515,"question":"Which among the following sentence is not correct about the organelles?","option1":"They are found in all Eukaryotic cells.","option2":"They are found in multicellular organisms.","option3":"They coordinate to produce the cell.","option4":"They are small sized and mostly internal.","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"They are found in multicellular organisms.","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":516,"question":"Name the process in which the passage of water goes from a region of higher concentration to a region of lower concentration through a semi permeable membrane?","option1":"Diffusion","option2":"Osmosis","option3":"Both a) and b)","option4":"Neither a) nor b)","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Osmosis","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":517,"question":"Name an organism which contains single chromosome and cell division occurs through fission or budding?","option1":"Eukaryotes","option2":"Prokaryotes","option3":"Bacteria","option4":"Primitive organism","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Prokaryotes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":518,"question":"Name the process in which the membrane of a vesicle can fuse with the plasma membrane and extrude its contents to the surrounding medium?\n\n","option1":"Exocytosis","option2":"Endocytosis","option3":"Osmosis","option4":"Diffusion","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Exocytosis","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":519,"question":"The jelly like substance present inside the cell is known as:\n\n","option1":"Cytoplasm","option2":"Ectoplasm","option3":"Nucleoplasm","option4":"None of the above","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Cytoplasm","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"},{"id":520,"question":"Blue green Algae are","option1":"Prokaryotes","option2":"Eukaryotes","option3":"Both a) and b)","option4":"Neither a) nor b)","parentCategory":"Science","category":"Chemistry","answer":"Prokaryotes","attended":null,"correct":null,"level":1,"adminEmail":"bhagath@manager.com"}]